https://www.inrock.com/data-privacy/

Follow us on
Copyright © 2020 Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. - All rights reserved
Follow us on—
Data Privacy
Privacy Statement
The integrity of your personal data is vital for Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc., and therefore, we welcome the extra transparency and protection of your personal data that the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) requires.
Whether you are a valued Customer, Supplier, Commercial or Administrative Intermediary, a Digital Registrant, a Physical Registrant, a Digital Visitor or a Facility Visitor, it’s important to us that you feel safe about how we treat your personal data.
Accordingly, we outline what types of personal data we collect from you, why, and what happens to your data while in our care. We also explain your rights under the GDPR and give you contact details in case you have any questions or requests about your data.
To understand what legal ground we rely on for each of the purposes described below, you are informed at the point of data collection where you will also be referred to this Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. Privacy Statement. Regarding retention periods, we store personal data only as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Statement unless a longer storage period is required for legitimate reasons, required by law or as necessary to justify or defend a legal claim. If you gave your consent for the use of your data, you may withdraw that consent at any time, and we will stop using your data. Your withdrawal of consent rights, as well as the specific retention periods, are provided to you in the information where we initially collected your personal data.
Definitions
We consider you:
a Customer if you or the company you work for has purchased our products or services;
a Supplier if you work for one of our many supplier companies from whom we purchase goods and services;
a Commercial or Administrative Intermediary if you work for one of our many distributors or other intermediaries such as our agents and customs brokers;
a Digital Registrant if you, for example, use our websites to:
request information about our products or services
register for newsletters or Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. sponsored events
apply to any Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. subscriptions or community forums
respond to survey or marketing communication
a Physical Registrant if you register with us in person at any of our events;
a Digital Visitor if you navigate our websites without registering as described under Digital Registrant;
a Facility Visitor if you visit any of our offices or facilities
Please be aware that you may appear in multiple categories as described above, depending on your relationship and activities with Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc.. For example, you may be considered a Customer, a Digital Registrant, and a Facility Visitor if you purchased our products, filled in one of our web forms and visited a Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. site at some point in time.
What types of personal data do we use and why?
Customers
Contact data (such as name, business address, email address, and phone number)
Effective and efficient communication: respond to your questions, send information about Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. products and services of interest to you; lead generation; fulfill our obligation to keep you informed about safety matters; communicate technical changes
Organizational data (such as which company and department you work in)
Efficient marketing: understand what products and services information you would be interested in receiving
Financial data (such as credit or payment information, bank account details)
Financial control: To assess credit and payment history, facilitate payments; to fulfill anti-money laundering obligations; and to manage rebates and refunds
Contract data (such as sales/purchase orders, shipment address or return to address), billing information, and other information collected under our customer and supplier contracts
Facilitation of order management, shipment and warranty; administration of service level agreements
Learning/training records (such as training attendance, completion of learning activities, competence data, qualifications)
Administer the customer/supplier/partner relationship and to communicate and develop new training opportunities you may be interested in
Individual preferences (such as language and food preferences)
Provide effective communication in the language of your choice and cater for dietary requirements. To offer you a pleasant experience in dealing with us
Service and warranty data (such as Repair and service history and claims)
For contract warranty fulfillment and for product development improvements and for fulfilling our/your maintenance obligations
Health and safety data (such as incidences occurring during visits to our test and manufacturing facilities, and any injuries that may occur from use of our equipment)
Fulfill legal obligations to record incidents and claims management. Improve safety in hazardous environments and to facilitate access for individuals with physical restrictions
Travel data (such as visa and passport information, travel costs, itinerary)
Arrangement of travel to Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. sites and events, including the arrangement of Visas
Suppliers
Contact data (such as name, business address, email address, and phone number)
Effective and efficient communication: respond to your questions, send information about Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. products and services of interest to you; lead generation; fulfill our obligation to keep you informed about safety matters; communicate technical changes
Organizational data (such as which company and department you work in)
Efficient marketing: understand what products and services information you would be interested in receiving
Financial data (such as credit or payment information, bank account details)
Financial control: To assess credit and payment history, facilitate payments; to fulfill anti-money laundering obligations; and to manage rebates and refunds
Contract data (such as sales/purchase orders, shipment address or return to address), billing information, and other information collected under our customer and supplier contracts
Facilitation of order management, shipment and warranty; administration of service level agreements
Learning/training records (such as training attendance, completion of learning activities, competence data, qualifications)
Administer the customer/supplier/partner relationship and to communicate and develop new training opportunities you may be interested in
Individual preferences (such as language and food preferences)
Provide effective communication in the language of your choice and cater for dietary requirements. To offer you a pleasant experience in dealing with us
Service and warranty data (such as Repair and service history and claims)
For contract warranty fulfillment and for product development improvements and for fulfilling our/your maintenance obligations
Health and safety data (such as incidences occurring during visits to our test and manufacturing facilities, and any injuries that may occur from use of our equipment)
Fulfill legal obligations to record incidents and claims management. Improve safety in hazardous environments and to facilitate access for individuals with physical restrictions
Travel data (such as visa and passport information, travel costs, itinerary)
Arrangement of travel to Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. sites and events, including the arrangement of Visas
Commercial or administrative intermediaries
Contact data (such as name, business address, email address, and phone number)
Effective and efficient communication: respond to your questions, send information about Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. products and services of interest to you; lead generation; fulfill our obligation to keep you informed about safety matters; communicate technical changes
Organizational data (such as which company and department you work in)
Efficient marketing: understand what products and services information you would be interested in receiving
Financial data (such as credit or payment information, bank account details)
Financial control: To assess credit and payment history, facilitate payments; to fulfill anti-money laundering obligations; and to manage rebates and refunds
Contract data (such as sales/purchase orders, shipment address or return to address), billing information, and other information collected under our customer and supplier contracts
Facilitation of order management, shipment and warranty; administration of service level agreements
Learning/training records (such as training attendance, completion of learning activities, competence data, qualifications)
Administer the customer/supplier/partner relationship and to communicate and develop new training opportunities you may be interested in
Individual preferences (such as language and food preferences)
Provide effective communication in the language of your choice and cater for dietary requirements. To offer you a pleasant experience in dealing with us
Service and warranty data (such as Repair and service history and claims)
Health and safety data (such as incidences occurring during visits to our test and manufacturing facilities, and any injuries that may occur from use of our equipment)
Health and safety data (such as incidences occurring during visits to our test and manufacturing facilities, and any injuries that may occur from use of our equipment)
Fulfill legal obligations to record incidents and claims management. Improve safety in hazardous environments and to facilitate access for individuals with physical restrictions
Travel data (such as visa and passport information, travel costs, itinerary)
Arrangement of travel to Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. sites and events, including the arrangement of Visas
Digital registrants
Contact data (such as name, business address, email address, and phone number)
Effective and efficient communication: respond to your questions, send information about Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. products and services of interest to you; lead generation; fulfill our obligation to keep you informed about safety matters; communicate technical changes
Organizational data (such as which company and department you work in)
Efficient marketing: understand what products and services information you would be interested in receiving
Individual preferences (such as language and food preferences)
Provide effective communication in the language of your choice and cater for dietary requirements. To offer you a pleasant experience in dealing with us
Information about the event you attended
Follow-up with you about more information regarding the product or service you showed interest in and to send you information about related products and services
Information about where you were on the Internet when you gave us your contact information and the material you downloaded from our website. Information about the Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. community blog or chat forums you participated in.
Follow-up with you about information regarding the product or service you showed interest in and to send you related product information
Information about Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. newsletters or other Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. content related material you have subscribed to
Follow-up with you about more information regarding the product or service you showed interest in and to send you related product information
Navigational data (such as IP address, cookies, session identifiers, browser type, web pages viewed and links clicked).
Operate and improve your overall web-browsing experience. Personalize your browsing experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product and service offerings of most interest to you. Allow us to better service you in responding to your customer service requests. Efficiently process your transactions. Administer a promotion, survey or other website feature
Physical registrants
Contact data (such as name, business address, email address, and phone number)
Effective and efficient communication: respond to your questions, send information about Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. products and services of interest to you; lead generation; fulfill our obligation to keep you informed about safety matters; communicate technical changes
Video, photo, time and location of recording, car/truck license plate number
Limited cameral surveillance. Cameras are stationed at certain unmanned gates to the industrial areas for the following purposes:
•	Open and close gates safely to prevent damage to vehicles and people
•	Control so no unauthorized persons gain access to the industrial area when opening gates.
•	Monitor exposed areas where there is a risk that unauthorized persons gain access to the industrial area unnoticed
•	To prevent and reveal property damages and related crimes
•	Investigate incidents and accidents.
Organizational data (such as which company and department you work in)
Efficient marketing: understand what products and services information you would be interested in receiving
Individual preferences (such as language and food preferences)
Provide effective communication in the language of your choice and cater for dietary requirements. To offer you a pleasant experience in dealing with us
Information about the event you attended
Follow-up with you about more information regarding the product or service you showed interest in and to send you information about related products and services
Digital visitors
Information about the event you attended
Follow-up with you about more information regarding the product or service you showed interest in and to send you information about related products and services
Navigational data (such as IP address, cookies, session identifiers, browser type, web pages viewed and links clicked).
Operate and improve your overall web-browsing experience. Personalize your browsing experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product and service offerings of most interest to you. Allow us to better service you in responding to your customer service requests. Efficiently process your transactions. Administer a promotion, survey or other website feature
Facility visitors
Contact data (such as name, business address, email address, and phone number)
Effective and efficient communication: respond to your questions, send information about Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. products and services of interest to you; lead generation; fulfill our obligation to keep you informed about safety matters; communicate technical changes
Organizational data (such as which company and department you work in)
Efficient marketing: understand what products and services information you would be interested in receiving
Video, photo, time and location of recording, car/truck license plate number
Limited cameral surveillance. Cameras are stationed at certain unmanned gates to the industrial areas for the following purposes:
•	Open and close gates safely to prevent damage to vehicles and people
•	Control so no unauthorized persons gain access to the industrial area when opening gates
•	Monitor exposed areas where there is a risk that unauthorized persons gain access to the industrial area unnoticed
•	To prevent and reveal property damages and related crimes
•	Investigate incidents and accidents
Individual preferences (such as language and food preferences)
Provide effective communication in the language of your choice and cater for dietary requirements. To offer you a pleasant experience in dealing with us
Health and safety data (such as incidences occurring during visits to our test and manufacturing facilities, and any injuries that may occur from use of our equipment)
Fulfill legal obligations to record incidents and claims management. Improve safety in hazardous environments and to facilitate access for individuals with physical restrictions
Travel data (such as visa and passport information, travel costs, itinerary)
Arrangement of travel to Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. sites and events, including arrangement of Visas
Information about the event you attended
Follow-up with you about more information regarding the product or service you showed interest in and to send you information about related products and services
Location, date and time of visit information
Travel and transfer arrangements; welcome messages
License plate number of vehicle
Facilitate and manage parking permits
Attention
In an attempt to provide you with increased value, we may include third party links on our website. These linked sites have separate and independent privacy policies. Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. is not responsible for the practices of these third-party websites and so your use of those websites will be in accordance with their privacy policies.
Sharing information with parties outside of Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc.
Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. does not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer your personal data to outside parties except as provided below based on Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc.’s legitimate interests to provide you with the high quality, useful products, and services you have come to expect from Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc.. We may transfer your data outside only if we have assured an adequate level of protection in the receiving country such as through the Sandvik intra-group data transfer agreement, the European Commission’s Standard Contractual Clauses with third parties or as otherwise required under national data protection law.
We may share data about Digital Visitors, Customers and Registrants to our website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our websites, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep your personal data confidential. More detail about this can be found at our specific Cookie Information pages.
Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. may share data about a Digital Visitor, Facility Visitor, Customer, Registrant, or Supplier with another Sandvik company if necessary to respond to you.
We may share data about Digital Visitors, Facility Visitors, Customers and Digital or Physical Registrants within the Sandvik group and with Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. business partners like authorized resellers or distributors so they can market and sell relevant Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. products and services to you, and so that we may jointly host product demonstrations and other events for you.
We may have to release information about Digital Visitors, Facility Visitors, Customers, Suppliers, or Digital and Physical Registrants to the appropriate authorities or other relevant third parties in order to enforce our privacy policies or to protect Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc.’s rights, property, or safety. We may also have to release your data to government authorities when a legal obligation compels us to.
Blogs, chat rooms and the like
Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. may provide blogs, chat rooms or bulletin boards on our website. Any personal information you choose to submit in such forum may be read, collected, or used by others who visit these forums. These non- Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. third parties may in their own discretion send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for these third parties’ handling of your personal data.
We post a list of customers’ references and testimonials about our products and services only upon consent of each customer.
Your rights
You have the right to:
know what data Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. holds about you;
restrict, under certain circumstances, our processing of your data;
have access to your data
have it corrected if inaccurate or out of date.
Additionally, you may object, based on your personal circumstances, to our processing of your data for our legitimate interests or object to our decisions about you based on profiling or automated decisions using your personal data. In some cases, you may require us to completely erase your data from all our files, and in other cases you may require us to provide your data in a machine-readable format and have the data transferred to another company. To exercise any of these rights, please visit our privacy statement.
If we collect personal data based on your consent, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. You may exercise this right by clicking on “withdrawing consent” or clicking on the “unsubscribe” link located at the bottom of Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. marketing emails or web forms where we obtained your consent.
Data collected from other sources
There may be times when Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. collects data about you from another source than yourself. This could happen, for example, when our Business Partners or Suppliers provide us with information about you. We also collect personal data from public sources such as social media. We
News — 2020-02-03
Sandvik Brazil – INROCK & HDD
News — 2020-02-03
Sandvik Mexico – INROCK & HDD
News — 2020-02-03
Sales Area Andean & South Cone – INROCK & HDD
News — 2020-02-03
Sandvik Brazil – INROCK & HDD
Copyright © 2020 Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. - All rights reserved
Follow us on
Copyright © 2020 Inrock Drilling Systems, Inc. - All rights reserved
We use cookies that make the web page easier to use. Read more
I accept
I accept
